(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-06T22:41:21.258090",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
MORI CALLIOPE BIRTHDAY LIVE
01 AZKi
02 NERISSA RAVENCROFT
03 TOKINO SORA
04 HOSHIMACHI SUISEI
05 MORI CALLIOPE
Uncut Rock!!
Rivals and Equals
[Song: Rivals and Equals]
base instincts take control
like primal ways of a warrior
is it glory you're after, like me?
underestimated everywhere I turn
taking aim, but it doesn't make a difference at all
I got a million different enemies I cannot recall
you're rocking up to a battle when you know that you'll fall
hidden motivation, watch it all burn
I gotta tell you
I never liked you
now, would I lie to you?
let me ignite you
when thunder crashes down
when the world caves
under my pressure, there'll be no one to save
where is your pride,
your human will to survive?
was it just empty words for your grave?
I reach inside this soul
now all that remains
is delusion and decay
'cause of you, I live this way
we're not rivals
we're not equals
you're just confused
never strikes twice in the same spot
So go ahead and run up on me till you get your shot.
I see the weapon that you're hiding, come on, ready or not.
Another life and you would never give a second thought.
Thinkin' your pride's different than mine
Ticking all your vital signs off
But we still gotta
protect all our friends from our enemies...
Wouldn't you agree?
Forged in fires of hell
God can't betray you
If I'm a fallen angel
What does that make you?
I'm not debasing myself to see the same view
When it's your pride on the line
No one can save you from mine
We're not rivals!
We're not equals!
Ahem, minasan!
Ahem, everyone!
Yeah, yeah! Woo!
This is... Woo, thank you!
This is Mori Calliope... Mori Calliope, yes!
Thank you so much everybody for coming to my birthday live!
Here is the hashtag, #UNCUTROCK, right here, right here, right here!
Check it out, everybody!
Today's theme is obviously birthday, right? Because it's my birthday!
And so, if you look behind us, we've got stones!
Oh my gosh! What kind of stones, I wonder?
Maybe birth stones, depending on the guest, I suppose.
Well, Mori Calliope is diamond, so...
Of course, you will see white behind me.
Yes, and the idea is to sing original songs with guests,
and also my own songs. And I'm looking at the comments right now.
Now, the show is in very high quality, so there's like a pretty big lag...
but I'm looking. Woo! Woo!
There's a lot of clapping.
Holy cannoli!
Holy cannoli is right.
Konbanwa, konbanwa!
Good evening, good evening!
Komento mite masu.
I'm looking at the comments.
Sugoi! "Happy birthday, happy birthday."
Wow, amazing! "Happy birthday, happy birthday."
Happy birthday wish, arigatou gozaimasu.
Thank you so much for the birthday wishes.
And you know what? Behind me is not only stones, but...
I also have a fabulous band joining me!
Yes, that's right! Live band.
Thank you so much to the band for coming.
Now, in particular, we have somebody that Mori Calliope...
really respects.
Today, Park-san is here with us!
Calli-chan, happy birthday.
Thank you!
Kyou wa yoroshiku onegaishimasu.
I look forward to working with you today.
Yoroshiku onegaishimasu!
I look forward to working with you too!
Park-san is one of my favorite bass players ever.
He's done two songs for me,
in particular, Orpheus and Sepia.
Orpheus to Sepia no beesu yatte kuremashita.
He played the bass for Orpheus and Sepia.
Park-san wa sugoi rispekto shitemasu. Hai.
I really respect Park-san. Yes.
But I have so many wonderful members in the band today,
and also guests as well, and...
I don't want to take up too much more time, but...
anyway, we should probably sing with guests,
because I want to showcase all that we've been practicing too, together. So...
Let's go ahead and begin.
The first guest, come on!
I can't control myself
閉ざした世界
In a closed-off world,
かすかに聞こえる音
I can faintly hear a sound.
世界で二人きりみたいだ
It feels like it's just the two of us here.
届きそうな手
Hands almost touch,
すれ違った心が
but our hearts drift apart,
ちょっと痛むんだ
and it hurts just a bit.
ここで待って
Wait for me here
決められないままで
I'm stuck in uncertainty,
戸惑い溢れてしまうよ
hesitating, too much confusion spilling out.
もう何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it again and again,
零れた想いを数えて
counting all the feelings that have overflowed.
何度も繰り返した
Repeating again and again,
世界
the world,
開くのを待っている
waiting for it to open up.
壊れた世界
In this broken world,
回り続ける針は
the hands keep spinning,
ちぎれた意識繋いでいく
with a frayed consciousness connecting us.
歪んだ金属音
The distorted metallic sound resonates,
鳴り響く心に
hitting my heart
ちょっと響くんだ
just a little.
ここで待って
Wait for me here
記憶繋げないまま
Memories can't connect,
狂って壊れてしまうよ
I'm going mad and breaking down.
もう何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times now,
神様に願いをかけて
making a wish to God.
何度も繰り返した
Repeated it so many times...
世界 世界
This world, this world...
開くのを待っている
...is waiting to open up.
もう何も要らないから
Because I don't need anything else anymore...
零れた想いは戻らない
Spilled feelings will never return.
何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times...
世界 世界 開くのを
This world, this world, waiting for it...
もう何度も繰り返した
I've repeated it so many times now,
神様に願いをかけて
making a wish to God.
何度も繰り返した
Repeated it so many times...
世界 世界
This world, this world...
開くのを待っている
...is waiting to open up.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Our first guest is AZKi-senpai!
AZKi! 右手にマイク、左手に地図、
AZKi! Mic in my right hand, map in my left,
あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！
I'll guess your heart! GeoGuesser!
カリオペちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
Calliope-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！バースデーです！誕生日です！
Thank you so much! It's my birthday! It's my birthday!
誕生日かーる！
The birthday girl!
ありがとうございます。さっき一緒に歌った曲、大好きです！
Thank you. I absolutely love the song we just sang together!
ありがとうございます！なんとAZKiのオリジナル曲を一緒に歌わせていただきました！
Thank you! We got to sing AZKi's original song together!
そうですよ！ずっとバンドアレンジやりたかったから、選びました！
That's right! I've always wanted to do a band arrangement of it, so I chose it!
めっちゃ熱かったです！ / やったー！
It was so hot! / Yay!
楽しかったよね！バンドの演奏も凄かったです！
It was so much fun! The band's performance was amazing too!
ありがとうございます！イェーイ！
Thank you! Yay!
あ、ちなみに、ステージを見てほしい！
Oh, by the way, take a look at the stage!
いや、すごい！めちゃくちゃピカピカ光ってる！
Wow, incredible! It's shining so brightly!
ピカピカスストーン！ / ピカピカスストーン！
Sparkly stones! / Sparkly stones!
そう、素敵ですよね！ / 素敵なステージです！
Yeah, it's lovely, isn't it? / It's a wonderful stage!
ちなみに、 / ちなみに？
By the way... / Yes?
AZKi先輩の誕生石は知ってます？
Do you know AZKi-senpai's birthstone?
AZKiの誕生石は、7月なんですけど、ルビー！この色！
AZKi's birthstone is for July... it's ruby! This color!
そう！なりました！ / すごい！
Yes! That's what it became! / Amazing!
色が変わるんですね、今日は。 / そうですよね。
The colors change today! / That's right.
すごい！めちゃくちゃ赤です！綺麗！
Incredible! It's so red! Beautiful!
そうですね。めっちゃ綺麗だから、一緒に写真撮りたいなと。
Indeed. It's so beautiful, I'd love to take a photo together.
あ、撮りたい！撮りたい！せっかくだから！
Oh, I want to! Let's do it, since we're here!
Take screenshots! Screenshot!
ピース！ / ピース！
Peace! / Peace!
いい感じです！ / イェーイ！
Looking good! / Yay!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! ありがとうございます。
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Thank you so much.
じゃあ、まあ、生ライブだから、やっぱり水飲みたい。
Well, since it's a live concert, we should probably drink some water.
水飲もう！カンパイ！
Let's drink! Cheers!
カンパイ！Cheers!
Cheers! Cheers!
Okay, okay. やった！
Okay, okay. We did it!
じゃあ、次、次の曲！
Now then, the next song!
お、次の曲は何かな？
Oh, I wonder what the next song is?
もう一曲ありますよね、一緒に。
We have one more song together, right?
あります！
We do!
さっきAZKi先輩のオリ曲やりましたね。
We just did AZKi-senpai's original song.
今回は、カリオペのオリジナル曲です！
This time, it's Calliope's original song!
The next song is Calliope's original... 未来島!
The next song is Calliope's original... Future Island!
奇奇怪怪な海に浮かぶ島 Hectic
An island of bizarre mysteries floating in the sea, Hectic.
世界変える未来島のラボ
Changing the world, the Egghead Lab.
最大級の夢 叶えるよ願望
I'll grant your greatest dreams and desires.
未来のお宝 探しちゃおう
Let's search for the treasures of the future!
天才！が引き起こす発想の奇跡
Genius! The miracle of inspiration triggered!
脳内で終わらせない夢のファンタジー
A dream fantasy that won't just end in our minds.
世界！ひっくり返るテクノロジー
World! A world-flipping technology!
大体！叶えちゃうラボラトリー
Mostly! A laboratory that makes it all happen!
サッカルド スウェッジ そのピタゴラス
Saccardo, Swedge, and Pythagoras,
アトラス ヨーク 毒に悪に 載せてライド
Atlas, York, Shaka, and Lilith, let's ride!
湧き出すアイデア止まらない
Ideas keep gushing out, never stopping,
忙しすぎて猫の手も借りたい
so busy we'd even take a cat's help.
海も何もかも越えてゆく海賊を
The pirates crossing the seas and everything else,
常識変えてゆく発明を
and inventions changing common sense.
そんな奴らに今憧れてきた
I've always admired people like that,
次は誰が王になる？
so who will be the next king?
無限の夢
Infinite dreams,
未来の知恵
future wisdom,
ひらめきを巻き起こせ エッヘッド
stir up inspiration, Egghead!
無限の夢
Infinite dreams,
未来の知恵
future wisdom,
過去も世界も飛び越して
leaping over the past and the world!
ベガパンク
Vegapunk!
革命をここから
Revolution starts here...
ベガパンク
...Vegapunk!
危険な海に浮かぶ島 エッグヘッド
An island floating in dangerous seas, Egghead.
世界変える未来島のラボフェーズ
The labophase of Future Island that changes the world.
This mind is undefeated, until my goal's completed.
Let's keep on searching for the treasure of "to-come."
Genius! A miracle idea, gotta set it free.
Mysterious! Fantastic dreams are burning up inside of me.
Deliriously! Turn the world around with new technology.
Here we come! A laboratory cast upon the sea.
Truth fades into evil, then to contents of mind.
Right into knowledge, greed and violence, six satellites.
Ideas can't stop rushing out, stop thinking they might.
Could use a hand or two, I'm busy working into the night.
The pirate king who braves the ocean while in search of elysian.
A ruler of invention that can modify all reason.
Once watched in jealousy, no someday I've gotta be...
...next on the throne, I know what I've got to do!
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom...
ひらめきを巻き起こせ エッグヘッド
...arouse inspiration, Egghead!
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom...
過去も世界も飛び越して
...leaping past both the past and the world!
ベガパンク 生み出すよ アイディア
Vegapunk, I'll create ideas!
ベガパンク
Vegapunk!
ベガパンク 革命をここから ベガパンク
Vegapunk, revolution starts here, Vegapunk!
Whoa! Oh right!
Okay, let's go!
言うこと聞かなきゃ振りかざす正義
If you don't listen, I'll brandish justice!
世界守る軍団の大義
The great cause of the army defending the world.
秘密巡る怪しいたくらみ
Mysterious conspiracies surrounding secrets.
過去の記憶に隠された狂気
Madness hidden in memories of the past.
真実追う危険な遊戯
A dangerous game chasing the truth.
謎に満ちた理想の夢のエネルギー
Ideal dream energy filled with mystery.
天才が見せる世界のかたち
The shape of the world shown by a genius.
どこへ向かう未来の島 エッグヘッド
Where is it headed, the Future Island, Egghead?
Thank you, Yakushiji-senpai! Bye-bye!
See you later!
Alright! Woo! Everybody welcome to the stage, Sora-senpai!
Happy birthday!
Yeah!
Okey dokey 返事はいいけど
Okey dokey, the answer is fine, but...
冗談なら笑えないよ
...if it's a joke, I can't laugh.
渋滞 曖昧 どっちを向いちゃうの
Congested, vague, which way am I going?
蜃気楼に手を伸ばした
I reached my hand out to the mirage.
微熱のような夢物語
A dream story like a slight fever,
そんな光は見ない振りしていた
I was pretending not to see such light.
ざわめく鼓動 まだ行かないで
Stirring heartbeat, don't go yet.
幻じゃ嫌だよ 私を奪って
I don't want it to be an illusion, steal me away!
魅惑の dancing dancing night
The alluring dancing, dancing night,
拡がって 収まんない universe
expanding, uncontrollable universe.
君の表情は 私の森羅万象を
Your expression will rewrite...
書き換えちゃうかもね 責任重大ね
...my whole world. You're highly responsible!
一切合切
Every single bit of it,
dance dance dance we are dancing reed
夢中になって絡み合った ゼログラビティ
Becoming absorbed, intertwined zero gravity.
構わず
Regardless of everything,
dance dance dance just a dance just a dance
声は 闇に預けたまま
leaving my voice in the darkness.
目を覚ましても 離れないで
Even if I wake up, don't leave me.
maybe needy 正気じゃないのよ
Maybe needy, I'm not in my right mind.
体温が忘れられない
I can't forget your body temperature.
誰彼 そんなんじゃないから
It's not just anyone, so...
独り占めして euphoria
...monopolize me, euphoria.
気にしてない様な言葉は装飾で
Words that seem unconcerned are just decorations,
メイクの様には流せない
they can't be washed away like makeup.
360° 偽りだって
Even if it's 360 degrees of lies,
隠しきれぬような 私に構って
take care of me as if you can't hide it.
嬉しいなんて crazy crazy love
Calling this happy is crazy, crazy love.
摩天楼から連れさらって
Take me away from the skyscraper.
君の表情は 私の深層心理を
Your expression will swap out...
すり替えちゃうのよ 責任重大ね
...my deep psyche. You're highly responsible!
過ぎ去ったネオン 残像 shooting star
The neon lights that passed by, the afterimage of a shooting star.
Alright! 盛り上がって！
Alright! Let's get excited!
Woo! Hey! Hey! Come on! Hey! Hey! Woo!
グライダーみたいに漂えば
If I drifted like a glider...
幸も不幸もなかった
...there would be neither happiness nor unhappiness.
指先で また君を探している
With my fingertips, I'm looking for you again.
その声を聴かせてよ 私に構って
Let me hear that voice, take care of me.
私にかまって
Pay attention to me,
教えてよ 恋 of 先っぽ
tell me the tip of love.
広がって収まらない不安
This growing, uncontainable anxiety...
君の存在は 私の将来待っても
Even if your existence waits for my future,
踏み込んだんだよ 付き合ってよ ねぇ
I've taken the plunge, so go out with me, okay?
Dance, dance, dance, dance, dance, yes! Dancing Reed!
夢中になって 絡み合って 繋ぐメロディー
Intertwining in trance, connecting the melody.
Move on! Dance, dance, dance, just a dance, just a dance, just a dance!
これは闇に熱く響くもの
This is something that echoes hotly in the darkness.
目を覚ましても 離れないで
Even if I wake up, don't leave me.
Yes! Our second guest is Tokino Sora-senpai!
はい！みんな、楽しんでる？ときのそらだよ！カリちゃん、ハッピー1stアニバーサリー！
Hi, everyone! Are you having fun? I'm Tokino Sora! Calli-chan, happy 1st anniversary!
Thank you!
そら大先輩！来てくれてありがとうございます。ずっと一緒に歌いたかったから。
Sora-daisenpai! Thank you so much for coming. I've always wanted to sing with you.
あ、本当ですか？ありがとう！
Oh, really? Thank you!
嬉しいですよ、マジで。やっと！
I'm so happy, seriously! Finally!
やった！ヘイ、ヘイ、ヘイ！
Yay! Hey, hey, hey!
ヘイ、ヘイ！
Hey, hey!
可愛いよね。
She's so cute, isn't she?
すごい、すごいたくさん踊りました！
Amazing, we danced so much!
あ、踊ったね！
Yeah, we did!
いいね、アイドルパワー！ドキドキ。
Nice, idol power! My heart is pounding.
ドキドキ？
Pounding?
Yes! Oh, oh, Calli, X...
X trending number three in Japan!
Thank you so much! It's trending number three in Japan!
Oh, congratulations!
トレンドやった！
We're trending! Yay!
やった！
Yay!
ありがとう！たくさん使ってね、please!
Thank you! Please use the hashtag a lot, please!
Please!
Thank you so much! Ah, I'm so happy. ありがとう。
Thank you so much! Ah, I'm so happy. Thank you.
イェーイ！そしてなんか今回、大好きな曲、一緒に歌いました。
Yay! And this time, we sang a song that I really love together.
はい！
Yes!
Dancing Reed!
Dancing Reed! Wow, すごいのなんか、party, happy!
Dancing Reed! Wow, it's so amazing, like a party, happy!
Yeah!
いいですよね、大好きです。
It's great, I love it.
Danceable!
Danceable! めっちゃ良かった。
Danceable! It was so good.
あ、ありがとう。ちょっとほら、エメラルド来た！
Ah, thank you. And look, emeralds came!
ね！綺麗！緑！
Right! Beautiful! Green!
綺麗ですよね。Thank you! お誕生日月ですよね？
It's beautiful, isn't it? Thank you! It's your birth month, right?
そう、5月の誕生石、エメラルドです。
Yes, May's birthstone is emerald.
Emerald! お、わ、すごい良い発音。
Emerald! Oh, wow, such great pronunciation.
本当？ありがとう。Nice English, nice English, very good. そうですよね。
Really? Thank you. Nice English, nice English, very good. Yes, indeed.
ちなみに、写真撮ろうか？
By the way, shall we take a picture?
あ、撮る！
Oh, let's take one!
Let's do it!
いいすね。
Nice.
Yay!
この写真もアップしてね、X。
Please upload this photo to X too!
よろしくね！Yes, よろしくね。
Please do! Yes, please do!
わぁ、楽しい。じゃ、お水飲みましょう。
Wow, so fun. Well, let's drink some water.
あ、お水。
Oh, water.
いいんですか？
Is it okay?
乾杯！
Cheers!
飲んだ方がいいすよね。
We should drink, right?
そうね、お水は大事。
Yeah, water is important.
そうだよ。はぁ、楽しいな、生ライブ。
Yes, indeed. Ah, live performances are so fun!
楽しいね！
It's fun, isn't it!
もう一曲、一緒に歌いたいんですけど、大丈夫ですか？
I'd like to sing one more song together, is that okay?
もちろん！
Of course!
Let's do it, okay?
Now, everyone, please listen to this next song.
You'll understand why I chose it because Sora-senpai is in the PV for this song.
Please enjoy my original song, Dawn Blue.
つかまえて、ほら
Catch it, look,
このshooting star
this shooting star.
A world of our fiction awaits...
Dawn Blue
[Song: Dawn Blue]
ずっと同じ毎日に迷いがあっても
Even if there were hesitations in the same everyday life,
気づかないふりをしてたんだ
I pretended not to notice.
ほんのちょっとの勇気がまだ出せなくって
A little bit of courage I couldn't muster yet...
まどろむ宇宙で彷徨っていた
Wandering in a drowsy universe...
夜空に浮かぶ星に願いをかけるんだ
Making a wish upon a star floating in the night sky.
I hope...
抱いてる夢を絶対諦めたくない
The dream I'm holding, I definitely don't want to give up,
走り出すから
because I'll start running.
追いかけて今あのshooting star
Chasing after that shooting star now,
見たことのないストーリー進んでいくんだ
I'll keep moving forward in a story I've never seen before.
いつの日かきっと
Someday for sure,
描いた世界へ
to the world I sketched out,
辿り着けるように
so that I can reach it.
Let go of the days you thought mattered
So life goes on, tomorrow's rolling in
Is it the world we know, or the dream we...
...dream we sought so long?
もっと 誰でもない 自分になりたいんだ
I want to become myself, and no one else.
新しい風が 心を揺らした
A new wind has shaken my heart.
It takes something to believe...
the wish we were promised could really come to life.
And so, if this is how the story goes,
to find that strength inside, I'll remember who I was back then.
You took my hand, and you said...
つかまえて、ほら この shooting star
Go forth and seize this shooting star!
さあ、まずは一歩踏み出して 恐れずに行こう
Come, let's take a step forward devoid of fear.
いつの日にかきっと まだ見ぬ世界へ
Hoping that someday it will bring us to a world we've yet to see,
辿り着けるように
so that we'll finally arrive.
夜明けに咲いた月が
The moon blossoms in the dawn,
眩しいブルーの空に溶けてく
melting in the dazzling blue sky.
You and I, an undecided future, doesn't matter if the final truth hurts.
もうすぐ朝が動き出すから
Because soon, the morning will come.
抱きしめて 今 この shooting star
Hold onto this shooting star right now.
見たことのないストーリー
A brand new story we've never seen.
I'll be here betting on that fearsome heart, cuz you're that shooting star.
It's hopeless now, but maybe if you take that step into the darkness, you'll find me,
running by your side until the dawn.
In the end, it's you and me, us against tomorrow.
the world that we had dreamed, dry your eyes and don't look back!
Face the world that we had dreamed, dry your eyes and don't look back!
Back...
Thank you so much, Sora-senpai! また一緒に歌いましょう！
Thank you so much, Sora-senpai! Let's sing together again!
歌いましょう！ありがとう！
Let's do it! Thank you!
Thank you! Bye-bye! またね！
Thank you! Bye-bye! See you!
またねー！
See you!
See you! わあ、楽しいね、生ライブ。
See you! Wow, live performances are so much fun.
Oh man, this is so fun. I just love singing. I love singing live so much,
and you guys, thank you for being a part of it. Woo, nailed it. You think so?
Because Sora-senpai was by my side. It was awesome.
Now next, I'll be singing with a surprise secret guest, but it's a bit of a break for myself and the band right now...
...because we're going to go back in time to a time when I recorded something with a special guest.
With the power of technology, you'll understand what I mean...
...but let's go back in the past, and myself and the band are going to chill for a minute.
So please enjoy that special guest performance, and I'll see you guys soon...
...for the next live one very shortly. Okay, see you then. どうぞ！
...for the next live one very shortly. Okay, see you then. Here you go!
罪と蜜 (feat. Mori Calliope)
[Title: Sin and Honey (feat. Mori Calliope)]
そう 恋に落ちたんだ だけどきっと不幸に堕ちたんだ
Yes, we fell in love, but surely we fell into misfortune.
気づきゃ僕らは行為に及んでいた
Before we knew it, we had crossed the line.
アナタの策 故意によるものだったんだ 見事さ
It was all by your design, brilliant.
地獄への片道切符 理性奪い去るリップ
A one-way ticket to hell, lips that steal my reason,
妄想高揚本能暴走 so mellow
delusions rising, instincts running wild, so mellow.
今宵 本能 暴走 そう Mellow
Tonight, instincts run wild, yes, so mellow.
さながら脳に数枚のチップ
Like embedding several microchips into my brain,
埋め込む様な狂愛のキック
a kick of mad love.
「アタシ アナタの永久のVIP」
"I'm your permanent VIP,"
囁いた言葉ずっと離れずに
the whispered words never leaving me.
アナタに アナタに アナタに
To you, to you, to you,
相応しいヒトになれますか？
can I become someone worthy of you?
Right, you left me. 愛す you. So we did it, did it, did it, did it. Stop!
Right, you left me. I love you. So we did it, did it, did it, did it. Stop!
I love you my girl, I love you my boy
アナタを知って全ては過去になる
Knowing you, everything else becomes the past.
I love you my girl, I love you my boy
しあわせに満ちた未来を作ろうね
Let's build a future filled with happiness.
そう 愛し切ってどうかこんな僕を
Yes, love me completely, please, someone like me.
愛し切ってどうかこんなアタシを
Love me completely, please, someone like me.
Give me, give me, give me, give me love
ねえ アタシに退屈を着せないで
Hey, don't dress me in boredom,
とびきりのドレスとアナタのエスコートで
with an extraordinary dress and your escort.
赤く染まる絨毯の上歩く
Walking on the red carpet,
マムシじゃないけどアタシはスター
I'm no viper but I am a star.
ワガママは女のアクセサリー
Selfishness is a woman's accessory.
付き合うが男のデリカシー
Going along with it is a man's delicacy.
世界で一番のお姫様いくよ 3 2 1
The greatest princess in the world, here we go, 3, 2, 1!
Three, two, one
やっとアンタに会わせたげるわ
I'll finally let you meet...
愛しい我がインダス
...my beloved Indas.
薔薇のタトゥー口移す
Passing the rose tattoo with a kiss,
流し込むのよ罪の味
pouring in the taste of sin.
共犯ね これであなたは
We're accomplices now. With this, you...
私に 私に 私に
...for me, for me, for me...
ふさわしい人になりました
...have become a person worthy of me.
Right, do
Left, me
Eyes, youth
So we did it, did it, did it, did it
Stop!
I love you, my God
I love you, my boy
恨み辛み抱いて あなたと僕とで営み
Embracing resentment and bitterness, you and I go about our business.
I love you, my God
I love you, my boy
その味知る前には戻れない
We can't go back to before we knew that taste.
相愛したって どうかこんな僕を
Even if we love each other, please, to this kind of me...
愛したって どうかこんな私を
Even if you love me, please, to this kind of me...
君 君 君 君 ら
You, you, you, you all...
Hey! Hey! Hey! Come on everybody!
All right! Yeah, yeah!
みなさん！Welcome、syudouさんとカリオペ3D Birthday Live！
Everyone, welcome to syudou and Calliope's 3D Birthday Live!
サンキュー！Check it out!
Thank you! Check it out!
狂わし合うように 癒やし合うように
As if to drive each other mad, as if to heal each other,
求め合ってしまうのよ しょうがないじゃない
we end up seeking each other out, we can't help it, right?
与えられた天国より 選んだ地獄を
Rather than the heaven we were given, we chose hell...
あなたと二人ならどこまでも
...as long as I'm with you, to the ends of the earth.
I love you, my God
I love you, my boy
堕ちていく
We are falling.
I love you, my God
I love you, my boy
あなたを知ってすべては過去になる
Knowing you, everything else becomes the past.
I love you, my God
I love you, my boy
自堕落に満ちた未来を 繕うね
Let's weave a future filled with self-indulgence.
そう愛しきって どうかこんな僕を
Please, love this kind of me completely...
愛しきって どうかこんな私を
君 君 君 君 ら
You, you, you, you all...
そう愛し合ってしまえばこんな僕ら
If we end up loving each other, we...
ハッピーエンドにはお別れを告げ
...bid farewell to a happy ending.
君 君 君 君 ら
You, you, you, you all...
みなさん、どう思いましたか？
Everyone, what did you think?
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
楽しかった！
That was so fun!
イェイイェイ、スーパースペシャルゲスト、syudouさんが来ました！
Yeah, yeah! Our super special guest, syudou, has arrived!
こんにちは！
Hello!
デッドビーツのみなさん、こんにちは。syudouです。
Hello, Dead Beats. I'm syudou.
Yes, 自己紹介お願いします！
Yes, please introduce yourself!
はい、僕はですね、音楽をやってますsyudouでございます。そして、ハッピーバースデーカリオペさん！おめでとう！
Yes, I'm syudou, a musician. And happy birthday, Calliope! Congratulations!
あ、センキュー！ありがとう！ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you! Thank you! Thank you so much.
ライブも最高です！
The live show is amazing!
あ、ちなみに、ハイタッチしたい。いいんですか？
Ah, by the way, I want to do a high-five. Is that okay?
あ、いきますか？いきますか？
Oh, shall we? Shall we?
せーの、よいしょ、えい！
One, two, three... there!
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
ありがとうございます。イェイ！ちなみにsyudouさんは、音楽活動いろいろやってます。ね、どんな活動やってますか？
Thank you! Yay! By the way, syudou-san, you do various musical activities, right? What kind of activities do you do?
そうですね、僕はボカロPですね。ボーカロイドで楽曲を作ったり、シンガーソングライターとして歌を歌わせていただいたり、そして色んな方に楽曲を提供させていただいたり、そんな活動をさせていただいております。
Well, I'm a Vocaloid producer. I make songs with Vocaloid, sing as a singer-songwriter, and provide songs to various artists. That's the kind of work I do.
イェイ！もちろん私知ってるけど、なんか大ファンだからね。
Yay! Of course I know, because I'm a huge fan!
嬉しいです。あの、ライブも以前来ていただきまして
I'm so glad. You even came to my live concert before.
そうですね。日本武道館ライブめっちゃ楽しかった！
That's right. The Budokan concert was so much fun!
いや、本当にありがとうございました。僕も楽しくて、めちゃくちゃ盛り上がったんで、嬉しいです、今日出られて。
No, thank you so much. I had a lot of fun, too, and it was so energetic. I'm really happy to be here today.
こちらこそ、私もすごい嬉しいですね。あの、このステージ、どう思いますか？
Likewise, I'm really happy too. What do you think of this stage?
ね、これすごいですよね。後ろからこの高さも含めて。僕ちょっと高いとこ苦手なんで、落ちないように気をつけながらやらないとなと思うんですけど、最高です、これ。
Right, this is amazing. The height, including what's behind us. I'm a bit bad with heights, so I have to be careful not to fall, but this is awesome.
まあ、かなり高いけど、気をつけてね！
Well, it is quite high, so please be careful!
本当に高いですよ、下見えないからね。
It really is high, I can't even see the bottom.
やべえ。
That's crazy.
え、でも、あ、そういえば、なんかテーマが誕生日だから、あの、ちょっと知りたいね。syudouさんの誕生日はいつですか？
Ah, but speaking of which, since the theme is birthdays, I'd like to know. When is your birthday, syudou-san?
僕の誕生日は9月ですね。September.
My birthday is in September. September.
September. Septemberですね。
September. September, I see.
あの、Septemberの、誕生石、バースデーストーンは、サファイア。
And the birthstone for September is sapphire.
サファイア、はいはいはい。
Sapphire, yes, yes, yes.
ほら、ステージは、サファイア、スタ、サファイア、サファイア。
See, the stage is sapphire... star... sapphire, sapphire!
あ！そういうことだったんだこれ！
Ah! So that's what this was all about!
僕に合わせていただいて、ありがとうございます。たまたまですけど、あの、服も、この青で、帽子も青で合ってたんで
Thank you for matching it to me. It's a coincidence, but my clothes are blue, and my hat is blue too.
相性がいい。
It's a perfect match.
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい、そうですね。ありがとうございます。
I'm so happy. That's true, thank you.
すごい、めっちゃいい感じですね。
Awesome, it feels really great.
いいですね。嬉しいですね。
It's great. I'm so glad.
Wow. え、次の曲は、syudouさんが書き下ろしてくれたやつですね。
Wow. The next song is one that syudou-san wrote for me, right?
そうですね、あの、僕がすごくカリオペさんの、もちろん楽曲大好きなんですけど、カリオペさんのカッコよくて強くて、すごく美しいみたいなところを引き出せるような楽曲として作らせていただいた曲でございますね。
That's right. I absolutely love your music, and I wrote this song to bring out your cool, strong, and beautiful sides.
ありがとう。いや、めっちゃいい曲、本当に、なんか大好きな曲だから。
Thank you. It's such a great song, really, because I absolutely love it.
あ、嬉しい、ありがとうございます。
Oh, I'm glad. Thank you.
マジで本当に感謝してます。
I'm truly, deeply grateful.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
今回、一緒に歌いたいと思います。
I want to sing it together with you this time.
初めてですね、一緒に歌うのは、これはね。
This is the first time we're singing it together.
初めてです。
Yes, the very first time.
カリオペさん、呼んでくれてありがとうございます！
Calliope, thank you so much for inviting me!
いいえいいえ、こちらこそ！
No, no, thank you! Same here!
じゃあ、それで聞いてくださいね。でも、しゅどうさん、
Well then, please listen to this next. But, syudou-san...
紹介してください！
...please introduce it!
それではお聞きください、
Now then, please listen...
LET'S JUST CRASH!
LET'S JUST CRASH / 作詞：syudou、Mori Calliope / 作曲・編曲：syudou
[Song: LET'S JUST CRASH / Lyrics: syudou, Mori Calliope / Music & Arrangement: syudou]
Hey hey, 皆さん！
Hey hey, everyone!
Yeah! Let's go!
Hahaha! Hey, hey!
Hey, you got eyes and ears, but you don't look or listen
In other words, you're useless, every last one of ya
And that's why I'm gonna send you all to hell! All of humanity!
声援背負い颯爽と登場 そういうんじゃねぇ
Making a grand entrance, carrying everyone's cheers... I'm not that type.
I'm just the type you'd forget, so don't waste your time
千切れ腐りかけの chain, going insane, somebody's gotta pay / while I live with the pain, laugh at me now, I'm the one you can't tame, huh?
A broken, rotting chain, going insane, somebody's gotta pay / While I live with the pain, laugh at me now, I'm the one you can't tame, huh?
低俗で最低の天才 そういうんでいい
A vulgar and trashy genius, you can call me that.
想いが募る場所に花は咲くから
Because flowers will bloom where our feelings gather...
Let's riot! Get back, you're trash!
掃き溜めで希望を積み上げていくんだ
We'll build up our hope from this rubbish pile!
頂から高らかに笑え
And laugh out loud from the top.
Lose control!
美しき理想を汚してくる野郎は
Those bastards who come to ruin our beautiful ideals...
Heads will roll! 誰だ一体？誰だ一体？誰だったとしても
Heads will roll! Who are they? Who are they? No matter who it is,
この理想は無理だろって
...even if they say this dream is impossible...
誰が言ったとしても叶えてこうぜ
...no matter who says it, let's make it come true!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Let's go! Verse 2! Listen!
正解不正解の解答 どうだっていい
Correct or incorrect answers, I don't care about any of that.
そんなとっくのとうに超えた場所に俺は立っている
I'm already standing in a place far beyond that.
Meaningless problems, everybody's got 'em and they can't be satisfied until somebody's at the bottom, so what?
You think you're special 'cause you got some grit and hunger? We ain't getting any younger, thinking let's just crash
心が通う時に魂が叫ぶ
When our hearts connect, our souls will scream!
Get back, you're trash!
ドブネズミの様に気高く生きるんだ
We'll live nobly, just like sewer rats!
俺が通る今すぐに退け Let's riot!
I'm passing through, so get out of my way right now! Let's riot!
Get back, you're trash!
掃き溜めで希望を積み上げていくんだ
We'll build up our hope from this rubbish pile!
頂から高らかに笑え
And laugh out loud from the top.
Lose control!
美しき理想を汚してくる野郎は
Those bastards who come to ruin our beautiful ideals...
Heads will roll! 誰だ一体？誰だ一体？誰だったとしても
Heads will roll! Who are they? Who are they? No matter who it is,
この理想は無理だろって
...even if they say this dream is impossible...
誰が言ったとしても叶えてこうぜ
...no matter who says it, let's make it come true!
3, 2, 1, let's go! Hey, hey, hey...
しゅどうさん、ありがとうございました！
syudou-san, thank you very much!
Thank you, Calliope!
叶えてこうぜ！
Let's make it come true!
でも、まだまだ終わってないすね、皆さん！
But we're not done yet, are we, everyone?
Alright! Let's just CRASH!
ありがとうございます！バイバイ、しゅどうさん！
Thank you very much! Bye-bye, syudou-san!
Bye-bye! Thank you, Dead Beats and Calliope!
Peace!
Ah, everyone, that was so fun. I really respect syudou-san as an artist.
He does a lot of his work himself for his songs. You know, writes, composes, sings, and everything. He's really cool, so big ups to syudou-san!
But I think it is about time that maybe we get back to the future...
...the present, where I'm performing with all my friends right now.
Yes, but that was a lot of fun, and... Ah, as I thought. Right on time!
It looks like it's time for me to get back to the future...
...and go sing with all my friends again back in the present... future... I don't know, none of this makes any sense. Let's go! See you there!
Blue World / 作詞：Nerissa Ravencroft / 作曲・編曲：syudou
[Song: Blue World / Lyrics: Nerissa Ravencroft / Music & Arrangement: syudou]
Walking an empty road
Nowhere for me to go
lost and lonely
yeah it's only me
burnt out like candle light
left blazing through the night
melting slowly
until nothing else is left of me
colored in shades of grey
watching the days pass in front of me
longing to find a way
i can fly away
i'm drifting through this blue, blue world
it's always been clear to me
how cruel the world can be
my shadow's the only one beside me
no love to call my own
no notifs on my phone
sunken silence
has engulfed the very life i lead
colored in shades of grey
watching the years pass in front of me
memories i wish would stay
always fade away
i'm lonely in this blue, blue world
though my heart is torn
and my weary wings are worn
just tonight, can't i dream
of a better life
with happiness inside?
colored in shades of grey
watching my life pass in front of me
maybe it's not too late
if i can't escape
i'll have to make my own way
colored in shades of grey
palette in hand, i can make a change
i'll try to find the strength
take a breath and paint
bring color to this blue, blue world
Wow, beautiful, Nerissa! You're so great!
Ah, thank you for coming!
After that emotional song, now we're all energetic!
We gotta hype everybody!
Hey, introduce yourself!
Thank you, thank you. It is my birthday!
But who is this lovely lady I'm singing with right now?
Who could I be?
Hi darlings! This is hololive English -Advent-'s devilish diva,
the one, the only, Nerissa Ravencroft!
here with you today at your birthday party!
Wow! Kakkoii! So cool!
Wow! How cool! So cool!
Arigatou gozaimasu!
Thank you very much!
Wow, you're so awesome, Nerissa. Thank you so much.
Thank you so much for letting me sing your Shouji Meguro song together with you!
We both love Shouji Meguro.
We both have a Shouji Meguro original song!
Actually, my first time performing, I got to be with you!
Yeah! No, seriously, it was so fun. It's always fun singing with a friend, so thank you for letting me be a part of it.
We got to harmonize too!
Yeah! I did my best to learn the harmonies and, you know, try to remember and stay consistent.
You did amazing. You impressed me.
Thank you so much. Well, I guess we ought to talk about...
...your birthstone. Because now we're going to talk about your birthday, even though it's my birthday.
Do you know your birthstone's a topaz?
Yes! It's so pretty! My birthday is November 21st, I'm a Scorpio, and... it's so pretty!
It matches your hair. Your little hair clips.
Oh my gosh, it just positively lights you up, your glow.
How about we take some pictures in front of the stone?
Let's do it. All right, here we go.
Peace? Peace?
Peace?
どっちでも。
Either one is good.
Oh, facing each other?
Feel a little sexy.
いい感じ。
Very nice.
Yes, please! Oh my gosh, please use the hashtag lots and post lots of pictures, okay?
Actually, just so you know, Nerissa, Genta on the drums is the one who played for our original song, OVERRIDE!
Oh my gosh!
Thank you! ありがとう, Genta. Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you, Genta. Thank you!
So awesome. Really appreciate you. Thank you. So many wonderful band members and guests. I feel very lucky...
We are lucky to have you. Thank you, Nerissa.
Do you want a drink of water before we start?
Yeah, immediately.
お水... And... mm-hmm.
Water... And... mm-hmm.
Okay.
Yeah, I think we're ready for another song then. How about that?
I am too. Let's do it.
Yes! Next up is Calliope original song... please enjoy Orpheus.
Yes! Next up is Calliope's original song... please enjoy Orpheus.
All right! Thank you so much, Nerissa, for coming to hang out!
Let's finish this off with a bang. Here we go!
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though / my heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah, thinking hurry up, Orpheus, time's a-wasting
Show me what you really wanna do!
Another late night, aimless dreaming / the day to day starts to call
Still got like a million deadlines, still bleeding red wine / my back up against the wall
I got my headphones on, walk home is long / dragging feet like I'm born to lose
'Til somehow they're tapping along to you-know-who's song / a melody I can't refuse
I'm outta line, but it's fine, you don't know my name / safe inside my own mind, I don't feel the shame, okay?
I know I get a little carried away / but we got music when there aren't any words to say!
Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way / gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
Now I'm in distress, you got me possessed, I might be obsessed / so let me get a little something off my chest, look
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though / my heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah, thinking hurry up, Orpheus, time's a-wasting
Show me what you really wanna do tonight!
It's my turn to show you how obvious I can be
Sometimes it feels like you're playing that guitar / for me and only me
Critics so loud, so predictable / they can't see what I can see
You're gonna wind up a star / you got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder / I wonder if it's enough
Cuz I'm not lying when I'm implying / you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional / baby, this could be real love?
Give me one chance and I'll take / you make me dance the night away
Get us help! Guh!
Now it's a game that I've played before / but with the way the scene changed
There is nothing you can blame me for
I'm talking TV screens, magazines, seen you in a couple dreams
Pictures up on every padded wall and floor
Always talking 'bout "no time to desire a lover" / so, why'd you paint your nails up in my favorite color?
I got an attitude just when it comes to you / so yeah, reality is kinda slipping out of tune
I'm never lost in the groove of somebody new / if it's devotion you're after, I'm staying true
So are you noticing me noticing you noticing me? / no disillusion but there's not a lot of guarantee
Cuz in my heart, feel a spark when you look this way / gimme a sign from the stage when you feel the same
You're strumming next to me, now I'm in ecstasy / and for the rest of the week I'm depression free
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though / my heart's beating to your song
Oh yeah, thinking hurry up, Orpheus, time's a-wasting
Show me what you really wanna do!
Tonight, it's my turn to show you how obvious I can be
So just as long as you keep playing that guitar... Yeah!
Critics so loud, so predictable / they can't see what I can see
You're gonna wind up a star! / You got me dancing so bizarre
This distance got me feeling fonder / I wonder if it's enough
Cuz I'm not lying when I'm implying / you're all that I've been thinking of
Maybe they'll call me delusional / baby, this could be real love!
Give me one chance and I'll take / you make me dance the night away
All right everybody! Today we have a very special band that's gathered today!
They're so cool!
Right? We gotta give them a proper introduction, Nerissa.
So let's do it! Are you guys ready to meet the band?
ドラムス、白川玄大！
On drums, Genya Shirakawa!
そしてベース、Yu Park！
Then on the bass, Yu Park!
そしてギター、芳賀義彦！
And on the guitar, Yoshihiko Haga!
そして最後は、今夜のマニピュレーター、大場映岳 -hana-！
And last but not least, tonight's manipulator is hana!
よし、ネリッサ、やってやろう！
Alright, Nerissa, let's take 'em out!
いいね。いくよ！
Sounds good. Here we go!
Orpheus get me going, taking space with the bass and drums.
So let's blow this joint, and if the feelings fight, then we can make a little music of our own tonight, come on!
Why are you walking away? I've got a lot to say, guess I'll save it for the next one.
I ain't trying to stress you, I must confess though, my heart's beating to a...
Oh yeah?
So hear me out, Orpheus, I'm thinking next time, we'll show you what we really want to do.
バイバイ、ネリッサ！一緒に歌ってくれてありがとう！
Bye, Nerissa! Thanks for singing with me!
楽しかったよ、最高だった！またね、愛してるよ、バイバイ！
I had a blast, you did fantastic! Yeah, see you later, love you too, bye-bye!
ねえ あたし いつも 勇気が足りないから
Hey, because I always lack the courage,
自分を大切にできないんだ
I can't seem to value myself.
痛い目を見ないと 気づけやしないんだ
I never learn unless I get hurt first.
あーあ 今日も キャラメルペインです
Ah, today is another caramel pain.
良い子でなんかいられないよ
I can't keep acting like a good girl.
だって世界はこんなにも極彩色で
Because the world is so richly colored,
甘ったるくて苦いし あ、待って 頭痛いし
it's bittersweet, and wait, my head hurts.
ヘトヘトで漂うだけの 24/7
Just drifting along exhausted 24/7.
ギリギリ感情抑えるなんて無理
Suppressing my feelings to the limit is impossible.
このままではいられないの日々
I can't keep living these days as they are.
ちょっと怖いけど
It's a little scary, but...
置いてくよ 置いてくよ 置いてくよ
I'll leave it behind, leave it behind, leave it behind.
今まで手にした イデオロギーも スタイルも
The ideology and style I've held onto until now.
壊れちゃっても 今がいいよ
Even if they break, right now is what's best.
だってあたしはあたしのままでずっといたいんだもん
Because I want to always stay just the way I am.
ルート？ムード？どうでもいーよ<
Route? Mood? I don't care at all.
トゥーザ ネクスト
To the next.
もっと危ないことしたら 勝ちでしょ
If I do something even riskier, I win, right?
何を犠牲にしたって しょうがないんだよ<
No matter what I sacrifice, it can't be helped.
フロムマイベッド この胸の痛みだけ抱いて
From my bed, clutching only this pain in my chest.
今日も キャラメルペインです
Today is another caramel pain.
ミルフィーユみたいに はぐらかしたって
Even if I dodge it like a mille-feuille,
いつかバレちゃうよ 腐っちゃうよ
it will get exposed eventually, it'll rot away.
痛いとか素直に君に言えてれば
If I could have honestly told you that it hurts,
今頃何か変わってたのかもね
maybe things would have been different by now.
好きなアニメもなくなっちゃうし
My favorite anime will be gone,
好きな人だって いなくなっちゃうんだ
and even the person I love will disappear.
寂しくなっちゃうな
It's going to get so lonely.
大切なことは ただ一つだけさ
The important thing is just one thing,
もう後悔しないように
so that I won't regret anything anymore...
前を向いて生きるということ！
To look forward and live!
置いてくよ 置いてくよ 置いてくよ
I'll leave it behind, leave it behind, leave it behind.
今まで手にした イデオロギーも スタイルも
The ideology and style I've held onto until now.
汚れちゃっても 気にしないよ
Even if they get dirty, I don't care.
だってあたしはあたしに恋していたいんだもん
Because I want to remain in love with myself.
愛してるよ 愛してるよ 愛してるよ
I love you, I love you, I love you.
さよならなんて 涙が出ちゃうけど
Saying goodbye brings tears to my eyes, but...
何を犠牲にしたって しょうがないんだよ
no matter what I sacrifice, it can't be helped.
フロムマイベッド この胸の痛みだけ抱いて
From my bed, clutching only this pain in my chest.
今日も キャラメルペインです
Today is another caramel pain.
ねえ あたし いつも 勇気が足りないから
Hey, because I always lack the courage,
自分を大切にできないんだ
I can't seem to value myself.
痛いくらいなら 少し我慢するんだ
If it hurts that much, I'll just endure it a little.
あーあ 今日も キャラメルペインです
Ah, today is another caramel pain.
イェーイ！最高！最高！
Yeeeah! That was awesome! The best!
やったー！やったー！
We did it! We did it!
久しぶりですけど おめでとう！ありがとう
It's been a while, but... Happy birthday! Thank you.
自己紹介お願いします
Please introduce yourself!
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！カリオペ、誕生日おめでとう！
The stellar rough diamond who swept in like a comet! Virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei! Calliope, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！誕生日！そしてね、メジャーデビューも4周年？
Thank you so much! Birthday! And also, is it your 4th anniversary of major debut?
そうですよね うわ、すごいよ！長い、おめでとう！
That's right. Wow, that's amazing! It's been long, congratulations!
そうですよね、それに一緒に歌いましたよね そう、4年前ね
That's right, and we sang together back then too, right? Yes, 4 years ago.
メジャーデビューしたときのライブで
at the live concert when you made your major debut.
一緒に歌わせてもらいましたね。
We sang together, didn't we?
ねえ、懐かしい。これ...これなんか...こんなんもやっとかない？
Yeah, so nostalgic! Shall we do... something like this?
やりました。たくさんやりました。
We did that! We did that a lot!
やばいよね、めっちゃいい思い出ですよね。
Crazy, right? It's such a great memory.
久しぶりに歌えて嬉しいね。
I'm so happy we got to sing it after a long time.
懐かしいポイント。
Nostalgia points!
そうですね、今回「Caramel Pain」一緒に歌いました。一番好きな星街すいせい曲です！
That's right, this time we sang "Caramel Pain" together. It's my absolute favorite Hoshimachi Suisei song!
わあ、嬉しい！
Wow, I'm so happy!
めっちゃいい感じだったね、ハモリとかも。
It felt really good, even the harmonies.
ねえ、本当に綺麗だったぜ。
Yeah, it was really beautiful.
ちなみに、ほら！ピカピカストーン！
By the way, look! Shiny stones!
Beautiful! 素敵ですよね。
Beautiful! They're lovely, aren't they?
素敵。え、すいせい先輩。
Lovely. Um, Suisei-senpai...
あの、私知ってるけど、誕生日はいつですか？
Uh, I already know, but when is your birthday?
私は3月の22！
Mine is March 22nd!
そうですね。
That's right.
先、先月、先月...
Last, last month, last month...
Yes! ですので...
Yes! And so...
ほら、アクアマリンが誕生石！あ、アクアマリンだ！もうぴったりよね。
Look, aquamarine is your birthstone! Oh, it's aquamarine! It matches perfectly.
私知らなかったよ、自分の誕生石がアクアマリンって。そう、ぴったりですよね、マジで最高。
I didn't even know my birthstone was aquamarine. Yes, it's perfect, seriously the best.
ねえ！同じ色だよ、もう。最高だぜ。
Right! It's the exact same color. It's awesome.
めっちゃ素敵ですよ、これ。
This is so beautiful.
めっちゃ綺麗だから、一緒に写真撮りましょう！あ、撮ろう！
It's so pretty, let's take a photo together! Oh, let's take one!
いいですか？ Let's go!
Are you ready? Let's go!
あ、私ね、やりたいものある。オッケー。えっとね...
Ah, I have something I want to do. Okay. Let's see...
これ？お、いいね。
This one? Oh, nice.
私これ。オッケー、やろう。Yeah.
I'll do this. Okay, let's do it. Yeah.
これ、何のポーズか分かる？ジョジョじゃない？
Do you know what pose this is? Isn't it JoJo?
違うよ。これ。
No, it's this.
ゴールデンウィンド！そう！
Golden Wind! Yes!
これかっこいいよね。ありがとう、Thank you so much.
This is so cool, isn't it? Thank you, thank you so much.
え、ちゃんと見てくれて、ありがとう。もちろん！大好きな曲ですよ。
Um, thank you for watching properly. Of course! I love that song.
Thank you so much, senpai. え、ちなみに、everybody, really quick, before we keep going...
Thank you so much, senpai. By the way, everybody, really quick, before we keep going...
お知らせあります。Yes, quick announcement about members-only. メンバー限定！
I have an announcement. Yes, quick announcement about members-only. Members-only!
アンコールがありますよ！やった！
There's going to be an encore! Yay!
A solo session, and we need to pick one song that I just performed with the amazing guests,
and, uh, I'm going to do a solo version of it. Yes. So you have one minute starting now!
1分ありますよ、vote! あの、カリオペはソロで歌いますよ。
You have one minute, vote! I, Calliope, will sing it solo.
さっきゲストと一緒に歌った曲。 Please vote! Everybody, you have one minute, go!
The song I just sang with the guests. Please vote! Everybody, you have one minute, go!
えー、何々？この後のメン限でソロで歌ってくれるらしいですよ。
Oh, what is it? Apparently she's going to sing it solo in the upcoming members-only stream.
えー、全部聴きたいよ！そうだね、全部、めちゃめちゃいい曲。全ての曲。
Aw, I want to hear all of them! I know, they're all such good songs. Every single one.
ねえ！でも、1曲だけ。Only one!
Right! But only one song. Only one!
ねえ、1曲だけですよ。選んでくださいね。選んでね。 Please, お願いします。
Right, just one song. Please choose one. Please choose. Please, I'm begging you.
どれがいい、どれがいいかな。Okay, お願いします。
Which one would be good? Which one, I wonder? Okay, please.
あー、楽しみ。頑張ります。ねえ。
Ah, I'm looking forward to it. I'll do my best. Yeah.
いや、カリオペ、本当にね、4年、メジャーデビューして4年。本当に駆け抜けてきたよね。
Calliope, really, it's been four years since your major debut. You've really been running through it.
色々やってますよね。ねえ。なんか、アニメのタイアップとかもね、たくさん決まって。
We've done a lot, haven't we? Yeah. And lots of anime tie-ins have been decided too.
決まりました。ねえ、嬉しい！So my dream...
They have. I'm so happy! So my dream...
そうですね、夢が叶った。ねえ、すごい、めっちゃ嬉しい。
Yes, my dream came true. Yeah, amazing, I'm so happy.
ありがとうございます。みなさんのおかげで。素敵な先輩のおかげでも。My inspiration.
Thank you so much. It's thanks to everyone. And thanks to my wonderful senpai too. My inspiration.
Thank you so much, everybody. Yay. So let's keep shooting for the moon. Yeah.
最高。そうだよ。
The best. That's right.
Oh, let's see. Oh, okay. Well, everybody is writing what they want... oh, okay. すごい、すごい、今、好きな曲...
Oh, let's see. Oh, okay. Well, everybody is writing what they want... oh, okay. Wow, wow, right now, their favorite songs...
おお、すごい、すごい！ねえ、すごい。 Many, many, many, many...
Oh, wow, amazing! Yeah, amazing. Many, many, many, many...
お、投票が？Go, go, go! Choose, choose, choose! 選んで、選んで！
Oh, the voting is? Go, go, go! Choose, choose, choose! Choose, choose!
始まっている？選んだ？嬉しいよ。
Has it started? Did you choose? I'm so happy.
始まっている？投票、もうちょっと長くやりますってよ。
Has it started? They said they'll keep the voting open a bit longer.
うん。 Okay, a little bit longer. Longer, longer time!
Yeah. Okay, a little bit longer. Longer, longer time!
Yes, please choose one. It's hard. 難しいと思うけど。ねえ。
Yes, please choose one. It's hard. I know it's difficult. Right.
Oh, let's drink water! あ、確かに。水乾杯！飲みましょう、はい。 Okay.
Oh, let's drink water! Ah, definitely. Water toast! Let's drink, yes. Okay.
チアーズ！Cheers! うん。
Cheers! Cheers! Mmh.
Thank you, senpai. 日本語で「チアーズ」何だと思う？
Thank you, senpai. What do you think "Cheers" is in Japanese?
うん、乾杯？乾杯。最近の流行りは何だと思う？
Um, Kanpai? Kanpai. What do you think the recent trendy word is?
うーん、チアーズ...けーぴー！けーぴー？けーぴー！けーぴー！イェーイ！
Hmm, Cheers... KP! KP? KP! KP! Yay!
え、たくさん使いたいと思う。使ってください。「乾杯」だけど「けーぴー」。
Oh, I want to use that a lot. Please use it. It means "Kanpai" but it's "KP".
けーぴー！けーぴー！けーぴー！Hey, hey, hey!
KP! KP! KP! Hey, hey, hey!
パリピが使ってます。パリピ！カリオペはパリピじゃないけど、使います。使います。
Party people use it. Party people! I'm not a party person, but I'll use it. I'll use it.
パリピ。Eh, party people in the house, let's go! はい。
Party people. Eh, party people in the house, let's go! Yes.
いいですね。うん。Nice. All right, is the voting closed?
Nice. Yeah. Nice. All right, is the voting closed?
どうかな、どうかな？決まったかな、決まったかな？どうかな、ちょっと分かんない。
How about it? Is it decided, I wonder? I wonder, I don't really know.
どうですか、みなさん？「お水美味しい？」だって。美味しい？
How is it, everyone? They're asking, "Is the water tasty?" Is it tasty?
Okay. Oh, close? あ、フワモコ！フワモコも見てくれてる？ Hi, FUWAMOCO! Hi! Thanks for coming!
Okay. Oh, closed? Ah, FUWAMOCO! Are FUWAMOCO watching too? Hi, FUWAMOCO! Hi! Thanks for coming!
I love fumo fumo.
Yeah, thank you, thank you! あ、今からスタート？
Yeah, thank you, thank you! Oh, now it's starting?
今からスタート。OK。
Now it starts? Okay.
今からスタート！
Starting from now!
Okay, no problem.
Push, push!
Go, go, go!
Push, please!
ちなみにカリオペも他にお知らせがあるんだけど。
By the way, Calli has some other news to share.
お！
Oh!
カバー曲もリリースします！
We are releasing a cover song!
Yes, check it out! The cover song is "In My Head" by natori.
Check it out, In My Head!
I like song.
I like that song.
You like it? / Yeah.
In My Head! In My Head!
Yeah, please listen to it. 聴いてくださいね。
Yeah, please listen to it. Be sure to check it out.
そう、あの、このライブの後、そしてそのあとは。
Right, after this live stream... And after that...
メンバー限定。
...is a members-only stream.
はい。
Yes.
Yes! And we have goods. Goods are going to be released very soon,
so I wanted to tell you guys about the goods. Goodsもありますので、
so I wanted to tell you guys about the goods. We have goods,
Limited! Limitedもありますので、ちゃんとお伝え...
including limited ones! I wanted to make sure...
...伝えたかったけど、
...to let you know, but...
配信の最後のほうは、CMを流しますので。
we'll show a commercial near the end of the stream.
お！
Oh!
But in about two minutes... 本当にもうすぐ、出るから、そのURL。
But in about two minutes... Really, the URL will be dropping soon.
準備しといて。 / そうですね、準備しといて。
Get ready for it. / Yes, get ready.
Ready? 心の準備もしといて。
Ready? Prepare your hearts too.
Yes, okay. Oh, oh, check it out! Here they are!
Yeah! かっこいい！
Yeah! So cool!
Dark fantasy Calli! Dark fantasy!
Thank you, I'm so cool! I'm like...
すごい。 / ...dark fantasy game boss.
Amazing. / ...a dark fantasy game boss.
あの、魔王みたい。 / Yes!
Like a Demon King. / Yes!
魔王イズ、イングリッシュ何？
What is "Demon King" in English?
魔王、あー、like...
Demon King... uh... like...
何て言えばいいかな？
How should I say it?
Dark... Dark... / Darkness... Dark... Dark King!
Dark King! Yes!
英語上手いよ！すごい！
Your English is so good! Awesome!
あ、投票終了。 / By the way,
Oh, voting has ended. / By the way,
Voting is over! It's done, yay!
Thank you so much! Oh my god, I'm excited to see what you guys chose.
Now then, we should sing one more song then, shouldn't we?
But look out for the goods! Goods URL is dropping soon, there's limited merch. Check it out! Goods買ってね。
But look out for the goods! Goods URL is dropping soon, there's limited merch. Check it out! Buy the goods!
よろしくね。
Please do!
Okay, so, たくさん休みましたね。だから、
Okay, so, we've rested a lot, right? So...
Let's sing one more song! / Yeah!
もう一曲、一緒に歌いたいと思います。いいですか、皆さん？
We want to sing one more song together. Are you ready, everyone?
いいですか？
Are you ready?!
Okay, ん、じゃあ、二人なら、やれるさ。
Okay. Well, if it's the two of us, we can do it.
やれるさ。
We can do it.
Next song is Gold Unbalance!
不確かな 物語に 勝ち取るは アイデンティティー
In an uncertain story, what we win is our identity
あれこれと 手を替え品を替え ドキリと胸を刺す激情
Trying this and that, using every trick, a passion that pierces the heart
感情は ノンフィクションで 喜怒哀楽
Emotions are non-fiction, with ups and downs
一心同体 一切合切の衝動
We're two bodies, one soul, a complete and absolute impulse
失敗も 成功も 味わえ
Taste both failure and success
我ら ゴールデン バディー
We are the golden partners
意味なんて ないような 世界で 偶然を 重ねた 光
In a world that seems meaningless, our light came together by chance
脈打つ 鼓動 誰にも なれない 言葉を 紡いでよ
Our pulsing heartbeat can belong to no one else, so spin your words
諦めんじゃねーよ 小さな 勇気 ひとつ ありゃ 十分
Don't you dare give up, a tiny bit of courage is more than enough
強気に 高みへと 圧倒 絶頂
Aggressively reaching the summit, absolute domination
2人なら やれるさ
If we're together, we can do it
back - to - back , no matter what
Back-to-back, no matter what
背負ったもん 武器に変わる spot
The burdens we carry turn into weapons in this spot
段違い 遠くまで飛ばす shout
Our shout flies further, on a whole different level
誰も邪魔できねぇ この rout
No one can get in the way of this route
1等 2等 3等りって はなから loser
First, second, or third place, you're a loser from the start
うざいくらい貪欲に ハート地獄から かっぱらっちまえ
Be annoyingly greedy, snatch your heart back from hell
loop 輪廻じゃない route は無限に
This isn't a looping cycle of rebirth, our routes are infinite
ありふれた 道じゃない 荊の道を 好む 玄人
It's no ordinary path, we're experts who prefer the thorny road
ハハハハ！
Hahahaha!
盛大に もう 笑えばいいさ
We might as well laugh out loud
才華 煩悩の グラデーション どうせなら ぐちゃぐちゃにしてよ
A gradation of talent and worldly desires, we might as well mess it all up
始めたのなら やり切る覚悟を 敗者と勝者の duet
If you've started, be prepared to see it through, a duet of losers and winners
劣等感 弾き出された 不条理の屑
Inferiority complex, the scraps of absurdity cast aside
振り払え貪欲に 志は消えない
Shake it off greedily, our resolve won't die
2人なら やれるさ
If we're together, we can do it
生きるってなんだ サボった者勝ちか そんなもの 握りつぶせ
What does it mean to live? Is it a game won by those who slack off? Crush such ideas!
握りつぶせ
Crush it!
上辺じゃいられない
We can't stay on the surface
エンタメ ライダー 人生賭け 駆け抜け
Entertainment riders, betting our lives and running through
絶望も 栄光も lemme see you fight back
Despair and glory, lemme see you fight back
どうなったって 何も変わらないんだって
No matter what happens, they say nothing changes
ミームされた 現実に 囚われて
Trapped in a memed reality
this life where we 're stuck taking chances
This life where we're stuck taking chances
飽き飽きしてんだろ？
You're sick of it, aren't you?
we 're living in a world with no direction
We're living in a world with no direction
reach out with our light ‘ till we make a connection
Reach out with our light 'til we make a connection
tearing the walls apart
facing it all , side by side
Facing it all, side by side
once again , it 's us against the world
Once again, it's us against the world
舐めんじゃねーよ
Don't look down on me!
本能をヒリつかせて
Let your instinct tingle
本物見せつけろ保存
Show them the real thing!
圧倒 絶頂 アンバランスを
An overwhelming, climactic unbalance...
踊れ
Dance!
Thanks for watching everybody! Thank you to my guests, thank you to the band!
Thank you everyone! Come hang out at members-gentei!
Thank you everyone! Come hang out at members-only!
Okay, またあともよろしく！
Okay, see you again later!
Yeah, and buy the goods! That's about all you guys, I'm Mori Calliope, peace out, see ya!
Let's go, yeah!
Bye!
Yeah, what's up, you crazy skeletons?
I mean...
Dearest Dead Beats, the hour is finally upon us.
The sale of Mori Calliope's birthday celebration goods is about to begin.
On this most auspicious day, you've been granted a great blessing by Death herself.
A most fortunate occurrence for thee, that such a glorious chest should appear before thine eyes.
Let's take a peek at what the Goddess of Death herself has to offer, shall we?
The journey ahead is long and arduous.
It would do thee good to prepare for it with such luxurious treasures.
Firstly, wouldst thou find comfort in dear Death's embrace?
If it be so, take some warmth along thy journey
with this very large, rollable blanket featuring a most intimidating and battle-ready maiden—yours truly,
designed by my favorite dark fantasy artist, Shimhaq! Woo!
The maiden in question possesses artworks and maps from this particular individual,
so I'd be most elated if you bought it for yourself.
Lay it across your bed, hang it on your wall, take it with you on an outing—think of the possibilities!
Secondly, whilst on thy noble journey,
thou mayest come to need a spark of aid.
If it be so, take one of these amulets.
The emblem of a knight to boost your strength.
The emblem of a samurai to grant you additional dexterity.
The emblem of a priestess to bestow additional health to thy weary body.
And lastly, the emblem of a necromancer to grant thee additional intelligence.
Alas, as Fortune is a fickle mistress, thou mayest only receive one in a set.
I pray thee be granted the boon most favorable to thy quest.
Or... or you could just purchase them all separately if you're looking to speedrun the experience, I suppose.
Thirdly, I present to thee the shining centerpiece of this valuable collection.
Take a moment of repose and sit beside this warm and healing light,
granted unto thee by Death herself.
A lantern to revive thee as many times as needed throughout even the most daunting of journeys.
May it light thy way to victory, or to sweet dreams, whichever is preferred.
Enjoy an elegant design chosen specifically by myself.
And of course, how could one continue a journey into vast and unforgiving lands without a source of healing?
Rejuvenate thyself with this generous flask, or rather glass,
that seems to refill endlessly upon rest at your lantern.
At least, I think it will. There really are no guarantees in this life,
but give it a try yourself, see if the myths are true.
Enjoy your favorite beverage during a night of exploring your favorite fantasy scenarios.
But naturally, it would do me no good to leave thee without, I don't know, a bedtime story?
To put this enchanting collection into context, so...
please enjoy a short audiobook-style recording of a fantastical story written by yours truly.
Believe it or not, we are the stars of this tale, so enjoy it on a rainy evening wrapped warmly in Death's embrace.
The... the blanket, I mean. You can use the flask also for like drinking at the same time, I don't know.
Just, you should really buy the full set.
And definitely do because lucky skeletons who act fast and purchase the entire set will be granted a hand-signed postcard
with a special color variant of Shimhaq's masterpiece rendition of Death herself.
The hand-signed option is in limited supply, so you must be swift.
For those that are unable to secure this extremely rare offering in time, do not fret.
By purchasing the entire set, a duplicated foil-stamped signature postcard will be sent as a bonus for your purchase.
That is all from me, Death's maiden and Dark Fantasy Enjoyer, Mori Calliope.
This year's goods are very different from my usual, but I wanted to pay tribute to a genre that I love so dearly,
and has really made every day of my job so wonderful and happy.
I am so grateful to you guys for coming to enjoy my show as well.
Comment and let me know what your favorite part was.
Be sure to like the concert so others may be recommended it, and subscribe if you enjoy Mori Calliope.
With that, I bid thee farewell.
And happy birthday... to me!
準備はよろしいでしょうか？
Are you ready?
はい、それでは行きます。
Yes. Here we go.
ご視聴ありがとうございました。
Thank you for watching.